in this video I'll be going over working
在这段视频中，我将继续工作
with clones which sounds similar to
使用的克隆听起来类似于
working with duplicates but it's
处理副本，但它是
actually a little different and I'll be
实际上有点不同，我会
explaining that in this video so let's
在这段视频中解释这一点，让我们
go ahead and get started here just for
去吧，从这里开始，只是为了
example I'm gonna go ahead and create a
例如，我将继续创建一个
little ellipse like that and a little
像这样的小椭圆和一个小椭圆
red circle like that I'm gonna convert
像这样的红色圆圈我要改信
it to a path and we're gonna do now is
它通向了一条道路，我们现在要做的是
I'm gonna go to edit clone and I'm gonna
我要去编辑克隆人，我要
click the option that says create clone
单击显示为创建克隆的选项
what that's gonna do is it's gonna
它要做的是它将会
create a cloned copy of that original
创建该原始文件的克隆拷贝
circle now you may be asking yourself
现在，你可能在问自己
well why don't I just create a duplicate
好吧，为什么我不创建一个副本
instead why don't it is right-click it
相反，为什么不右键单击它
and go to duplicate well this is
去复制井，这是
slightly different here this object this
这里略有不同这个对象这个
cloned object is linked to this object
克隆的对象链接到此对象
here so whatever I do to this object
所以无论我对这个物体做什么
it's gonna happen to that object as well
它也会发生在那个物体上
let me show you as an example I'll scale
让我向您展示一个我将扩展的示例
that down and that scales down as well I
那就缩小了，我也缩小了规模
turn that green that turns green as well
把那变绿的绿也变绿
I go to the paths I go to the other
我走这条路，我走另一条路
nodes tool might change the nodes and it
节点工具可能会更改节点并使其
happens to that as well this is
恰好也是这样，这是
virtually a copy of this object here and
这里实际上是这个对象的副本
anything I do to this will happen to
我对此做的任何事都会发生在
this as well if you notice here if you
如果你注意到这一点，如果你
want to look at the nodes there's no
想看看这些节点吗？没有
actual nodes here that I can edit if I
此处的实际节点，我可以在以下情况下编辑
want to edit this clone I have to edit
我想编辑这个克隆，我必须编辑它
the original clone first in order to do
原来的克隆人首先要做的是
that now if I want to make this clone
现在如果我想做这个克隆人
it's very own object and make it so
它是自己的东西，并使它成为这样
that's no longer linked to this object
不再链接到此对象的
right here what I can do is go to edit
在这里我能做的就是去编辑
clone and I can click on unlink clone
克隆，我可以点击取消链接克隆
and now it becomes its own object and if
现在它变成了自己的对象，如果
you notice here you can see there's the
你注意到这里你可以看到这里有
nodes and everything and when I go and
结点和所有东西，当我离开的时候
edit this object over here it doesn't
在这里编辑此对象它不会
happen to that object there so that's
发生在那个物体上，所以那是
how that works now let's go to edit
它是如何工作的，现在让我们来编辑
clone relink - copied okay how this
克隆重新链接-复制好了这是怎么回事
works is let me create another copy I'm
Works是让我创建另一个副本
gonna take this object I'll go to edit
我要拿着这个对象我要去编辑
clone create yet create clone and here's
克隆创建，创建克隆，这里是
a cloned object right here what I can do
克隆的物体就在这里，我能做什么
is instead of take instead of linking
是不是接受而不是链接
this clone to this object I can instead
这个对象的克隆我可以代替
link it to this object let me just edit
将其链接到此对象，让我编辑一下
that a little bit do something like that
有点像这样的事情
what I can do is I can copy that by
我能做的就是把它复制到
right-clicking it and going to copy or
右键单击它，然后复制或
you can just hit ctrl C on the keyboard
你只需按键盘上的Ctrl C键
and then I could take this clone right
然后我就可以把这个克隆人带回家
here and go to edit clone
点击此处并转至编辑克隆
relink - copied and what that does is it
重新链接-复制，这样做的目的是
real inks it to that object there if you
REAL会将其墨迹印到那个物体上，如果
notice here made it that same exact
注意，这里的情况与此完全相同
thing so that's how that works
这就是它的工作原理
you look here again edit clone select
您再次查看此处编辑克隆选择
original okay so let's say we have a
原创的，好的，假设我们有一个
bunch of objects here right I'm gonna
这里有一堆东西，我要
create a bunch of copies of this clone a
创建此克隆的一组副本作为
bunch of clones of the clone I'm gonna
一堆克隆人的克隆我要
mix these all together and shuffle them
把这些混合在一起，然后洗牌
all around and you want to select the
并且您想要选择
original so you can edit all of them but
原创，所以您可以编辑所有这些内容，但是
you don't know what you want is the
你不知道你想要的是
original so what you do is you just
所以你要做的就是
click on any one of them and go to edit
单击其中任何一个并转到编辑
clone select original and then it'll
克隆选择原创，然后它将
show you where the original one is and
告诉你原件在哪里，然后
then you can go and edit that further
然后，您可以进一步编辑它
like that so that's the basics of how
就像这样，所以这就是如何
clones work there's a couple of other
克隆人行得通，还有几个克隆人
things I want to show you here in this
我想在这里向你们展示的东西
menu clone clone original path that's a
菜单克隆克隆原始路径为
live a path that's a live path effect
活在一条路径上，这是一种活的路径效果
which is something that's totally
这完全是一件
different I'll be going over that in its
不同的是，我会在它的
own video and then there's create tiled
自己的视频，然后是创建平铺
clones which this is an entirely long
克隆，这是一段很长的时间
video in and of itself which I'll be
视频本身和本身，我将成为
going over next but that's the basics of
下一步，但这是基本的
how you can work with clones in Inkscape
如何在Inkscape中使用克隆